BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nahuel Brandán

contact@nahuelbrandan.com

| mahuelbrandan.com/en | 1 +54 9 3574 638119 | O Cba / Arg

in linkedin.com/in/nahuelbrandan | j github.com/nahuelbrandan | j stackoverflow.com/users/6125910

ABOUT ME -

With over 4 years of experience in software development, I have specialized in Python, working in both the web and aerospace industries. I collaborate efficiently in multidisciplinary teams, implementing best development practices, and enhancing technical documentation to ensure project reliability and scalability. Additionally, I hold a degree as a Computer Analyst.

EXPERIENCE -

Real Trends 05/2022 - Present

Backend Software Developer

Remote

- · Develop software based on Python, Django, Docker, and Celery, among other technologies
- Development of integration with MercadoLibre APIs to enhance product functionality
- Collaborate closely with other departments, using assertive communication, to create new functionalities

Satellogic 06/2022 - 09/2022

Backend Software Developer

Remote

- Refactored an application into two separate entities, reducing coupling and improving maintainability
- · Contributed to improve code quality through regular code reviews and technical discussions

Ascentio | Project: Sabia-Mar

08/2021 - 05/2022

Backend Software Developer

Remote

Satellite mission, with advanced technology for the study of the sea and the ocean.

- Developed contributions to satellite flight planning and communication modules, using Docker, FastAPI, API
- Created unit and integration tests, using Robot Framework, Postman, and Pytest
- Documented projects and development processes, using LaTex and Markdown

IncluIT | Project: Junar

03/2019 - 07/2021

Backend Software Developer

Cba - Arg

- Developed and maintained the backend base code of the system, based on Python, Django, and DRF
- Integrated Auth0 and Keycloak technologies as security layers in API management
- Upgraded Django versions and other +15 dependencies, to reduce the technical debt
- Optimized 30% performance in response time of the APIs, through cache management and refactors
- Managed technical onboarding to +10 new developers, providing guidance and technical support

EDUCATION

National University of Córdoba - Argentina

10/2018

Computer Analyst, equivalent to B.S in Computer Science (Graduated)

Cba - Arg

Career with strong emphasis on programming, analysis, and design of systems, databases, and computer networks, combining a solid theoretical understanding with practical skills.

COURSES

Platzi 01/2021 - 11/2023

Complete more than 100 courses and in constant learning in the professional online academy called Platzi, on topics such as: soft skills, English, Python, tools, and software development.

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python, C
- · Databases: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch
- Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework, FastAPI, Robot Framework
- Dev tools: Linux, REST API, Git, GitHub, Bash, Postman, Docker, Celery, Cache
- Languages: English (B1 intermediate), Spanish (Native)